Guide to the Ohio State University, Office of the President (Harold Leroy Enarson) Records, 1940s-2002 RG.3.J
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
- Accession Number UA.1993.0184, 1978-1982; 6.0 Cubic feet; (5) cartons
  - Executive Assistant and Director of Budget and Planning, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 23)
  - Budget Hearing Letters, 1981-1982 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 24)
  - Budget Advisory Committee, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 25)
  - Campus Planning, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 26)
  - Committee on Sports Broadcasting, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 27)
  - Vice President for Educational Services, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 29)
  - Vice President for Regional Campuses, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 30)
  - Lima Campus, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 31)
  - Mansfield Campus, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 32)
  - Marion Campus, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 33)
  - Newark Campus, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 34)
  - Vice President for Student Services, 1980 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 35)
  - Student Housing, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0001, Folder 36)
  - Athletics, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 1)
  - Fencing Team (Rodgers/Childs Situation), 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 2)
  - Football, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 3)
  - Association of American Universities, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 4)
  - Transportation Research Center Proposal, 1978-1979 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 5)
  - State Fiscal Crisis, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 6)
  - National Regulatory Research Institute, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 7)
  - Attorney General, State of Ohio, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 8)
  - General Assembly, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 9)
  - Federal Government, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 10)
  - Tuition Tax Credit, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 11)
  - Regan's Budget, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 12)
  - Bogen, Jenny, 1982 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 13)
  - Staff, President's Office Information, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 14)
  - Letters of Introduction, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 15)
  - Recommendations, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 16)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 17)
  - Athletic Council, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 18)
  - Student Financial Aids and Scholarships, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 19)
  - Black Student Demands, 1980 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 20)
  - Public Affairs, Vice President, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 21)
  - United Way, 1979-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 22)
  - Legislative Reports, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 23)
  - Battelle Memorial Institute, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 24)
  - Academy for Contemporary Problems, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 25)
  - National Center for Research in Vocational Education, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 26)
  - Board of Directors, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 27)
  - President's Club, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 28)
  - Development Fund, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 29)
  - Development Fund Gifts, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 30)
  - Development fund III, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 32)
  - Alumni Association, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 33)
  - Alumni Distinguished Teaching Awards, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 34)
  - Distinguished Service Awards and Distinguished Research Awards, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 35)
  - Faculty Club, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 36)
  - University Senate, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0002, Folder 37)
  - Patent Advisory Committee, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 1)
  - American Association of University Professors (AAUP), 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 2)
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 3)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU), 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Recruitment of Students, Promotion and Tenure, Graduate Degree Program, BER Courses, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 5)
  - International Programs, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 6)
  - Minority Affairs, Office of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 7)
  - Continuing Education, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 8)
  - Larry R. Thompson, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 9)
  - Vice President for Business and Administration, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 10-12)
  - Finance, Executive Director and Treasurer, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 13)
  - Public Safety, Division of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 14)
  - Admissions, Office of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 15)
  - Enrollment, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 16)
  - Fees and Tuition, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 17)
  - Registrar, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 18)
  - Charles Wilson Case, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 19)
  - Vice President for Personnel Services, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 20-21)
  - Department of Labor, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 22)
  - Affirmative Action, Office of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 23)
  - Affirmative Action, 1980 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 24)
  - Revised Affirmative Action Plan, Volume A, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0003, Folder 25-26)
  - Administrative Science, College of, 1979-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 1)
  - Griffith Foundation, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 2)
  - Agriculture and Home Economics, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 3)
  - O.D.A.R.C., 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 4)
  - Arts, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 5)
  - Biological Sciences, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 6)
  - Humanities, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 7)
  - Mathematics and Physical Sciences, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 8)
  - Social and Behavioral Sciences, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 9)
  - Journalism, School of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 10)
  - Social Work, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 11)
  - Education, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 12)
  - Engineering, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 13)
  - Don Scott Field, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 14)
  - Graduate School, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 15)
  - Dentistry College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 16)
  - Medicine, College of (Lancer Center, VA Clinic), 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 17)
  - Vice President of Health Sciences, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 18)
  - Search for Dean, College of Medicine, 1980 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 19)
  - University Hospitals Board Transcripts, 1980 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 20)
  - University Hospitals, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 21)
  - Health Services, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 22)
  - Vice President's Report, 1981 March (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 23)
  - Nursing, School of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 24)
  - Law, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 25)
  - Optometry, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 26)
  - Pharmacy, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0004, Folder 27)
  - Veterinary Medicine, College of, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 1)
  - Board of Regents, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 2, 4-5)
  - 1219 Cases, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 3)
  - Ohio Board of Regents Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 6)
  - Board of Regents Reports, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees, Miscellaneous, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 8)
  - Resolutions in Memoria, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 9)
  - Emeritus, Correspondence and Parking, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 10)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 11)
  - Special Assistant to the President, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 12)
  - President's Staff Miscellaneous Correspondence and Memos, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 13)
  - Council of Deans, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 14)
  - University College, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 15)
  - Ombudsman, 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 16)
  - Provost, Office of, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 17)
  - Regrets of Invitations (samples), 1981 (Box UA.1993.0184.0005, Folder 18)
- Accession Number UA.1994.0048, 1960-1981; 1.2 Cubic feet; (1) carton
  - Academic Computing, Advisory Committee on, 1972-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Committee, Title IX (Charles Batey), 1976-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 2)
  - Buildings - OSU Campus - Use Policies, 1960, 1969-1970, 1973 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 3)
  - Campus Grievances, Advisory Committee on, 1972-1977 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 4)
  - Campus Planning, Advisory Committee on, 1972-1981 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 5)
  - Cancer Research Center, Advisory Committee on, 1973 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 6)
  - Career Services Development Committee (Nester), 1978-1979 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 7)
  - China Committee, People's Republic of, 1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 8)
  - Computer Coordinating Committee, 1972-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 9)
  - Continuing Education, Advisory Committee on, 1975-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 10)
  - Development, Office of University - Monthly Reports (VP Smith, Robert G.), 1974 January-May (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 11)
  - Fawcett Center Policy - Third Floor, 1973 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 12)
  - Energy Conservation Coordinating Committee (Moulton), 1976-1981 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 13)
  - Engineering Experiment Station Advisory Council, 1972-1973 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 14)
  - Graduate and Professional Colleges Admissions Programs, Committee on, 1976-1978 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 15)
  - Health Education Service, Advisory Committee on (Dr. Cramblett), 1976-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 16)
  - Health Sciences Library, Advisory Committee on, 1973 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 17)
  - High School Advisory Board (Schaen), 1975-1981 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 18)
  - Housing Appeals Panel, 1972-1977 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 19)
  - Housing Panel of Ohio, 1976-1979 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 20)
  - Investment, Real Estate, and Leasing, Board of Trustee Committee on, 1980-1981 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 21)
  - Learning, Task Force on, 1977-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 22)
  - Medical Affairs, Office of - Monthly Reports (VP Meiling, Richard L.), 1972-1974 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 23-26)
  - Medical Affairs, Office of - Monthly Reports (VP Cramblett, Henry G.), 1974-1976 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 27-30)
  - Medical Research and Development Fund, 1979-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 31)
  - Medicine, College of - Practice Plan, 1979 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 32)
  - Mershon Auditorium, Executive Committee on the, 1973 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 33)
  - Natural Resources, Advisory Committee on the School of (Kuhn), 1972-1981 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 34)
  - Neighborhood Relations Committee, 1978-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 35)
  - Nisonger Mental Retardation Center, Policy Council, 1972-1974 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 36)
  - Parking and Traffic, Commission on, 1972-1979 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 37)
  - Placement and Related Services Committee, 1972-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 38)
  - Public Affairs, Office of - Monthly Reports (Special Assistant to the President; Gilbertson, Eric), 1974 August-1975 January (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 39)
  - Public Relations, Office of - Monthly Reports (Executive Assistant to the VP; Esmond, Robert V.), 1975 February (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 40)
  - Public Relations, Office of - Monthly Reports (VP Crawford, Edwin M.), 1975-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 41-47)
  - Public Safety, Committee on, 1976-1981 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 48)
  - Radiation Safety Committee (OSU), 1972-1973 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 49)
  - Real Estate Education and Research, Advisory Committee on (Provost), 1976 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 50)
  - Research on Animal Laboratories, Housing Standards, Procurement, and Feeding Programs, Advisory Committee on, 1973-1974 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 51)
  - Research, Development, and Related Activities Involving Human Subject, Program Review for, 1975-1978 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 52)
  - Research, Special Committee on CIA-Sponsored, 1977-1978 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 53)
  - Resource Planning, Advisory Committee on, 1974-1977 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 54)
  - Sculpture, Advisory Committee on Campus, 1976-1978 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 55)
  - Senate, Ohio Faculty, 1975-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 56)
  - Special Events, Advisory Committee on, 1972-1976 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 57)
  - Urban Affairs Committee, 1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 58)
  - Water Resources Center, Advisory Committee on the (Kuhn), 1973-1981 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 59)
  - Women, Advisory Committee on, 1972-1980 (Box UA.1994.0048.0001, Folder 60)
- Accession Number UA.1996.0086, 1972, 1974; 0.03 Cubic feet; (1) legal file folder
  - Capital Plan 1973-1979 and 1975-1981, 1972, 1974 (Box Small Accessions 20)
- Accession Number UA.1998.0142, 1971-1972; 0.02 Cubic feet; (1) file folder
  This series contains chronology and letters concerning the retirement of President Fawcett and the search for his successor, Harold L. Enarson, titled Presidential Search Chronology.
  - Presidential Search Chronology, 1971-1972 (Box Small Accessions 50)
- Accession Number UA.2000.0038, 1974-1980; 0.02 Cubic feet; (1) file folder
  - Agronomy, Department of, 1979 (Box Small Accessions 24)
  - Athletics, 1974 (Box Small Accessions 24)
  - Pre-Jennings, 1979 (Box Small Accessions 24)
  - University Honors Center, 1979-1980 (Box Small Accessions 24)
- Accession Number UA.2000.0113, 1972-1988; 0.4 Cubic feet; (1) 5" document box
  This series contains office files from the Enarson administration including minutes and correspondence from councils and committees such as the Athletic Council, Honorary Degree Committee, and the Steering Committee.
  - Alumni Awards for Distinguished Teaching Committee, 1972-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Athletic Council, 1974-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Bookstore Committee, 1975-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Calendar Committee, 1975-1988 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Committee on Academic Freedom and Responsibility, 1977-1979 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Committee on Academic Misconduct, 1972-1980 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Council on Student Affairs, 1976-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Distinguished Teaching Awards, 1974-1977 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Honorary Degree Committee, 1976-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Faculty Advisory Committee to the Chancellor of the Ohio Board of Regents, 1978-1980 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Faculty Advisory Committee, 1976-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - FCBC Materials: Board of Trustees, 1978-1979 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Library Council, 1974-1978 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Mershon Committee on Education on National Security: Kuhn, 1975-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Papers in Archives from the President's Office, 1978-1979 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Patent and Copyright Committee, 1978-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Program Committee, 1976-1980 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Recreation Sports Advisory Council, 1976-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Research Award Recipients, 1978 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Research Foundation Board of Directors, 1972-1980 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Rules Committee, 1977-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Senate Elections Committee, 1976-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
  - Steering Committee, 1977-1981 (Box UA.2000.0113.0001)
- Accession Number UA.2002.0052, 1963-1977; 0.2 Cubic feet; (1) 2.5" document box
  - Individual Publications, 1963-1977 (Box UA.2002.0052.0001)
  - Speeches, 1960-1977 (Box UA.2002.0052.0001)
- Accession Number UA.2003.0123, 2002 May 6; 0.08 Cubic feet; (1) file folder, (12) audiocassette tapes
  - Oral history interview transcript, 2002 May 6 (Box Oral History 2)
    Related Materials
    Also available online
  - Oral history interview transcript (first draft), 2002 May 6 (Box Oral History 2)
  - Oral history interview recording part 1, 2002 May 6 (Box Oral History 8, Box 7, Box Oral History 6)
  - Oral history interview recording part 2, 2002 May 6 (Box Oral History 8, Box 7, Box Oral History 6)
  - Oral history interview recording part 3, 2002 May 6 (Box Oral History 8, Box 7, Box Oral History 6)
  - Oral history interview recording part 4, 2002 May 6 (Box Oral History 8, Box 7, Box Oral History 6)
  - Oral history interview recording part 5, 2002 May 6 (Box Oral History 8, Box 7, Box Oral History 6)
  - Oral history interview recording part 6, 2002 May 6 (Box Oral History 8, Box 7, Box Oral History 6)
- Accession Number UA.2003.0132, 1981 August 19; 0.15 Cubic feet; (1) oversize folder
  - Ohio House of Representatives Resolution for Harold Enarson on his retirement, 1981 August 19 (Box Flat Items 28)
- Accession Number UA.2008.0093, 1974-1983; 0.4 Cubic feet; (1) 5" document box
  - Agronomy: Department of, 1979 (Box UA.2008.0093.0001)
  - Athletics, 1974 (Box UA.2008.0093.0001)
  - Basketball, 1979-1981 (Box UA.2008.0093.0001)
  - Football, 1979-1980 (Box UA.2008.0093.0001)
  - Football ticket requests, 1980 (Box UA.2008.0093.0001)
  - Honorary degrees, 1979-1983 (Box UA.2008.0093.0001)
  - International programs, 1981 (Box UA.2008.0093.0001)
  - Medicine: College of, 1978 (Box UA.2008.0093.0001)
  - Newspaper clipping procedures, 1979 (Box UA.2008.0093.0001)
  - University Honors Center, 1979-1980 (Box UA.2008.0093.0001)
- Accession Number UA.2010.0014, circa 1940s; 0.4 Cubic feet; (1) 5" document box
  This series contains correspondence between Enarson and his mother while he was working in Washington, D.C.
  - Correspondence, circa 1940s (Box UA.2010.0014.0001)
- Accession Number UA.2013.0036, 1980s; 1.5 Cubic feet; (2) artifacts
  This series contains a copy portrait of Harold Enarson, which hung in Enarson Hall (now Hale Hall), and a bronze plaque that accompanied the portrait in Enarson Hall, circa 1980s.
  - Harold Enarson copy portrait from Enarson Hall, 1980z (Item UA.2013.0036.0001)
  - Bronze plaque accompanying Harold Enarson portrait, 1980s (Item UA.2013.0036.0002)
- Accession Number UA.2016.0105, 1981 January 14 - August 1; 0.02 Cubic feet; (1) file folder
  - Appointment schedule for President Harold Enarson, 1981 January 14 - August 1 (Box Small Accessions 47)
- Publications, 1972-1975; 0.06 Cubic feet; (4) file folders
  These publications include both content from Enarson and his office during his presidency.
  - Budget Message, 1974-1975 (Box UA.RG3.PUB.0001)
  - China Trip, 1974 (Box UA.RG3.PUB.0001)
  - Legislative Relations, 1973-1975 (Box UA.RG3.PUB.0001)
  - Remarks and Speeches, 1972-1973 (Box UA.RG3.PUB.0001)
  - Budget Message, 1974-1975 (Box UA.RG3.PUB.0004)